Hello English learners.
Welcome back to English pod.
My name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today
we have another great
elementary lesson for you all.
That's right. We've
got a lesson for all
you sports fans out
there. Right. We're doing a
podcast on sports today.
We're starting off with basketball.
Uh-huh. So we've
got lots of language
about basketball and
sports in this lesson today.
Great. So let's take a look at our
vocabulary preview. Very capillary preview.
Two words for you today.
The first one is foul foul foul.
A foul. Basically it's an action in
a game that is not allowed. Right.
So if you're playing basketball and
you kick the other player, that's a foul.
That's a foul. That's
a pretty big foul.
Yeah. If you're
playing soccer and you
pick up the ball.
That's also a foul. Huh?
Our second word is ref. ref. R-E-F.
Also known as a referee. Mm-hmm.
Right. So a referee is
basically like the judge of
a game, the judge of the
game. So he's the one that
will say that was a foul. That was a foul,
exactly. Yeah. Ref. Also known as referee.
Okay. So two great
words. We're going to hear
them in our dialogue
and we're going to be
listening to two guys who are
watching a basketball game on TV.
Hey, is the game started yet?
Yeah, about five minutes ago.
Who's winning? Balls, of course.
What? That wasn't a
foul. Oh, come on, ref.
Don't worry. Shack always
screws up free throws.
You're right. He didn't make a shot. Yeah.
That was a great shot. Three-pointer. Yeah.
Did you see that? He traveled to the ref.
Didn't even call us. Ref needs glasses.
Hey, ref. Open your eyes.
Can't believe he didn't see that. Okay.
And the first quarter. All right.
I'm going to make a beer run.
All right. A really
common situation
whenever you're watching games with
friends, right? You need to get a beer.
We'll talk about that in a little while.
Let's take a look at language takeaway.
Language takeaway. Okay. Let's take a look
at our first word on language takeaway.
Free throw. Free
throw. Free throw.
Free throw. This one's
a bit hard to say, isn't it?
It's a little bit hard to explain, but if
you're playing basketball and if someone
fowls you, you get a
free throw. So that's when
all the players line up
around you and you can
throw the ball to the
basket without anyone
blocking you or. Right.
A little bit complicated,
but I'm sure the basketball
fans understand what
a free throw is. All
right, our next word is
make the shot. Make
the shot. Make the shot.
Let's listen to some
examples and we'll understand
the meaning of make
the shot. Example one.
I can't believe it. You made
the shot from the other
side of the court. Example
two. There's no way
he's going to make that
shot. He's way too far away
from the net. Example
three. If Gretzky makes
a shot, they're going
to win the Stanley Cup.
So it's clear now to make the shot is to
successfully thank the ball in the basket.
You can use this expression
in other sports as well, right?
Yeah, you can use it in hockey to make
the shot. You could also use it in golf
in a lot of different sports
that use the term to shoot.
Yes, shoot the ball.
So at any time you
shoot the ball, you can
make the shot. Exactly.
Okay, our next word
today. Three pointer.
Three pointer. Three
pointer. Three pointer.
It's a shot in basketball
when you get three points.
Yes. Usually this shot is
taken from further out.
Yeah, farther distance.
Yeah, so it's a little bit more
difficult to make the shot.
You know, sometimes
people might say a three
point shot or something
like that, but our English
pot learners, they
know. It's a three point.
Yeah, you'll sound
really knowledgeable,
really cool. Three
pointer. And our last word
today, travel to travel
travel. When you walk with
the basketball, well,
technically you're allowed
to take two steps
in basketball. Okay.
So when you take more than
two steps. So yeah, traveling
means to take more than
two steps with the ball.
Let's listen to the
dialogue a second time.
This time, it'll be a bit
slower so that we can
understand some of these
great phrases we just talked about.
Hey, has the game started yet? Yeah,
about five minutes ago. Oh, who's winning?
The bulls, of course.
What? That wasn't a foul.
Oh, come on, ref. Don't worry.
Shack always screws up free
throws. Yeah, you were right.
He didn't make this shot.
Yeah, that was a great shot.
Three pointer. Yeah. Oh, did you see that?
He traveled to the ref didn't even call it.
This ref needs glasses. Hey, ref, open your
eyes. I can't believe you didn't see that.
Okay, the end of the first quarter.
Hey, I'm going to make a beer run. Sweet.
All right, sports fans.
So now let's take a
look at fluency
builder. Fluency builder.
Okay, today on fluency
builder, we have two really
common words that you
would listen to while you're
watching a game. Yeah,
these are sort of slangy words.
Yeah, they're kind of a
common like informal
informal. The first one
that we have is screw up,
screw up, screw up,
screw up, to screw up.
Yeah, so this is a good way
of saying to make a mistake.
Let's listen to some
examples of how this word
is used. Example one. Jill, you
really screwed up this time. You fired.
Example two. This game is important. If
you screw it up, we're out of the finals.
Example three. I'm sorry.
I know I screwed up. Will you forgive me?
Okay, so screw up is mess
up. Yeah, make a mistake.
Make a mistake. Great.
And our last word on
fluency builder today,
a beer run. A beer run.
Beer run. So what is this
beer run? You run to get beer.
You go to the store and
get beer, get more beer.
So it's just an expression to meaning to
go and get more beer. Yeah, usually you're
watching a game or you're
at home with your friends,
you run out of beer, so
somebody has to make a
get some beer, go get
some beer, make a beer run.
Yeah.
Good block out of Simon.
Hey, is the game starting yet?
Yeah, about five minutes
ago. Who's winning?
Bulls, of course. What? That wasn't a foul.
Well, come on, ref. Don't worry.
Shaq always screws up free throws.
You're right. He didn't make a shot.
Yeah, that was a great
shot. Three pointer.
Yeah. Did you see that?
He traveled to the ref.
Didn't even call us. Ref needs glasses.
Hey, ref, open your eyes.
Can't believe it and see
that. Okay, the first quarter.
All right, I'm going
to make a beer run.
Okay, guys, I hope you
enjoyed our lesson today.
We'll be bringing you more
sports lessons in the future.
Yes. So if you have a particular sport that
you want to learn about, you can tell us
and we'll come to our
website, EnglishPod.com.
Yeah, and leave us your
comments or your suggestions
or any doubts that you
have. And we're always
there to answer it.
So we'll see you there.
Yes, until next time. Bye.